Guide to the Hapgood Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Correspondence, 1849-1950; Series I; 3.25; (8 boxes)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1939-44, n.d.
  - Craig, Nellie, 1920-43 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Cruikshank, Colin and Eva, 1931-47 (Box 2, Folder 55-57)
  - Cruikshank, Colin and Eva (Box 3, Folder 58-59)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1925 Apr 25 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - "D" general, 1911-46, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Davidson, Jo, 1940-46, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - De Lano, Agnes, 1925-39, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Dewey, John and Jane, 1941-43, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 64)
    Includes letter from John Dewey to Katrina [Johnson?]
  - Dos Passos, John and Katy, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1921-43 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc., 1946 Nov 25 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - "E" general, 1917-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Eastman, Max, 1941-48 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Everts, Elsie (Mrs. Frank J. Everts), 1913-44, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Everybody's Magazine, 1913 Oct 25 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - "F" general, 1914-45, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Farrar & Rinehart, 1930 Aug 1 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Fleishman, Leon, 1930, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Flynn, Edward J., 1940 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Fox, Duffield & Co., 1903-12 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1929-41 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Funk & Wagnalls Company, 1927-39 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - "G" general, 1922-47, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Clara Langdon Clemens, 1922 Feb 19 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Gallup, Donald, 1973, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Gastand, Fernande, 1919-20 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - General Electric Company, 1923 May 28 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Glaspell, Susan, 1923-24, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 84)
    See also: George Cram Cook, Box 2, folder 50; Nilla Cook, Box 2, folder 51
  - Glick, Harriet M., 1929-39, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Goldman, Emma, 1911-40 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Grundy, J. Owen, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - "H" general, 1865-1940, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Hackett, Francis, 1930 Dec 28 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Haggard, Edith (Box 3, Folder 90)
    See: William Morris Agency, Box 7, folder 231
  - Hand, Learned, 1918-40 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Harcourt, Alfred
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company Inc., 1936-40 (Box 3, Folder 92-93)
  - Hard, William, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1913-22 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Harrison Smith and Robert Haas, Inc., 1934 Aug 23 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Hartley, Marsden, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Harvard University, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Harvard University Press, 1945 Jun 1 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Havel, Hippolyte, 1940-44, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Henderson, Frank, 1925-30, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 101-02)
  - Henderson, Harry B., Jr., 1938-39 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Herrick, Robert, 1893-1938, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 104-05)
  - Herron, George D., 1923-25 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Hickok, Guy, 1922-28 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Hodder, Alfred, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Holly, Flora M., 1910-34 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Hopkins, Arthur, 1931 Mar 31 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Hopkinson, Leslie, 1895-1939, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Houghland, Wright, 1939-40 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Howe, Fred, 1938-40 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - "I" general, 1923-44 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - "J" general, 1917-47, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Jeffers, Una, 1936 Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Johannsen, Anton, 1911-35, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - John Adams Thayer Corporation, 1913 Aug 15 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - John Day Company Inc. Publishers, 1943 Mar 19 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Johnson, Russell T. and Katrina, 1938-44, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 120-21)
  - Johnson, Spud, 1930-31 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Johnstone, William Bard and Sally, 1928-40, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1932-40, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - "K" general, 1913-43, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Kaeselau, Charles, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Kaeselau, Marguerite (Mrs. Charles Kaeselau), 1930-43, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 127-28)
  - Kelley, John B., 1937-41, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Kemp, Harry, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Kennerley, Mitchell, 1939-43, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 131-32)
  - Kenton, Edna, 1913-43 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Kretchway, Freda
    See: The Nation, Box 6, folder 169
  - "L" general, 1912-41, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Leeuwen, N. van ("Dutchee"), 1923-29 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - L'Engle, Bill and Lucy, 1920-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Library of Congress, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Lippincott's Monthly Magazine, 1913-14 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1939-41 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - The Little Theatre, 1915 Mar 9 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - London, Jack, 1940 Apr 29 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Lorber, Herman ("Harry"), 1936-38, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Lovett, Robert Morss, 1888-1948, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 143-46)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge to, 1888-1948, n.d.
  - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1936-40, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1929 Aug 23 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1919-40, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 149-51)
  - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1912-30, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 152-55)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge from Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - "M" general, 1921-45, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - MacGowan, Eddie B. (Mrs. Kenneth MacGowan), 1935-45, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - McIntosh, Mavis
    See: McIntosh & Otis, Inc., Box 5, folder 159
  - McIntosh & Otis, Inc., 1940-41, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Marvin, Fred H., 1912-36, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Mason, C. P., 1940-41, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - The Masses Publishing Company, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1933 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - The Metropolitan Magazine, 1910 Oct 11 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Miller, Ruth, 1938-40, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1933-34 (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - The Musical Advance, 1913 May 13 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - "N" general, 1913-40, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 168)
  - The Nation, 1937 Jun 30 (Box 6, Folder 169)
  - New Hampshire Historical Society, 1934 Feb 20 (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - The New Republic, 1934-39 (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - The New York American, 1922 Aug 22 (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - The New Yorker, 1932 May 16 (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Noyes, Elizabeth W., 1849-64 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - "O" general, 1945, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - O'Brien, T. H., 1919 Dec 22 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - O'Neill, Agnes, 1934-39 (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - "P" general, 1913-48, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - The Pamphlet Press, 1942, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Pattison, Alice M. G., 1918-40, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 182)
  - Payson, Mrs., 1890 Apr 9 (Box 6, Folder 183)
  - Pearce, Charles A.
    See: Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc., Box 3, folder 67; and Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc., Box 3, folders 92-93
  - Perkins, Frances, 1913-35 (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Phillips Academy, 1917 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1938 Dec 15 (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - PM (Box 6, Folder 187)
  - Pyne, Mary, 1927-29, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 188)
  - "R" general, 1914-46, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Reed, John, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - Reitman, Ben L., 1940 (Box 6, Folder 191)
  - Richard G. Badger, Publisher, 1914 May 6 (Box 6, Folder 192)
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1921-32, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 193)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1935-46, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 194)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 195)
  - "S" general, 1864-1945, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 196)
  - Saben, Mowry, 1918-44, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Schmidt, Katherine L. (Mrs. Matthew, 1918-44, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 198)
  - A. Schmidt), 1921-39, n.d.
  - Schmidt, Matthew A., 1916-39 (Box 6, Folder 199)
  - Sheffield, Justus, 1923-41, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 200)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1940-42 (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1938 Nov 15 (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Stanwood, Frances Perot, 1937-44 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - Stearns, Linhart, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Steffens, Lincoln, 1913-32, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Stein, Gertrude, 1915 Jul 29 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Stein, Leo, 1934-42, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 207)
    See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1529
  - Sterne, Maurice, 1927-44 (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1920-48 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1940-41 (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Swan, Lucile, 1930, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - "T" general, 1897-1946, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 212)
  - Taylor, Helen K.
  - Temple, Helen, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 213)
  - Thomas Seltzer, Inc., 1922-24 (Box 7, Folder 214)
  - Torrence, Ridgley and Olivia, 1928-46, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 215)
  - Toy, Nancy, 1918-25 (Box 7, Folder 216)
  - "U" general, 1913-21 (Box 7, Folder 217)
  - "V" general, 1911-41 (Box 7, Folder 218)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1915-1940, undated (Box 7, Folder 219)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1919-38 (Box 7, Folder 220)
  - Vorse, Mary Heaton, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 221)
  - "W" general, 1870-1946, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1946 Oct 24 (Box 7, Folder 223)
  - Warner, Charles D., 1899 Dec 22 (Box 7, Folder 224)
  - Webster, George H., Jr., 1919 Feb 12 (Box 7, Folder 225)
  - Webster, Gertrude D., 1933-43, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 226)
  - Weinberger, Harry, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 227)
  - White, G. N., 1929 (Box 7, Folder 228)
  - Whorf, Benjamin Lee, 1916-18, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 229)
  - Wilder, Katharine Buell, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 230)
  - William Morris Agency, 1933-35 (Box 7, Folder 231)
  - William Morrow & Company Inc., 1934 (Box 7, Folder 232)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1913-14 (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - Winter, Ella, 1936-41, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 234)
  - Wolman, Samuel and Adele, 1925-44, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 235-37)
  - Woman's Home Journal, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 238)
  - "Y" general, 1931-46, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 239)
  - "Z" general, 1928 Sep 28 (Box 7, Folder 240)
  - Correspondence bearing given name or nickname only
    - A-B, 1908-32, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 241)
    - C-D, 1917-43, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - E-F, 1917-40, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - G-I, 1918-40, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - J, 1921-46, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - K-M, 1917-43, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 246)
    - N-R, 1898-1948, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 247)
    - S-W, 1925-44, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 248)
  - Unidentified, 1895-1948, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 249-52)
- Family Correspondence, 1849-1950; Series II; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  Series II, Family Correspondence (Boxes 9-21), contains correspondence between Hapgood and Boyce family members. It is arranged alphabetically first by author and there- under by recipient. Unidentified correspondence is placed at the end.
  - Backman, Elizabeth Hapgood to
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1934-39, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 253)
  - Bigelow, Sophia Holland Arms to
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson, 1882-92 (Box 9, Folder 254)
  - Boehncke, Paul Barton to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1918-33, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 255)
  - Bonnell, Alice Harrison to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1917-20, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 256)
  - Bonnell, Florence Mary to
    - Bonnell, Margaret Boyce, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 257)
  - Bonnell, Margaret Boyce to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1927 Jul 28 (Box 9, Folder 258)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1930-48, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 259)
  - Boyce, Charles to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1937 Sep 15 (Box 9, Folder 260)
  - Boyce, Helen Faith to
    - Boyce, Mary Ella Smith, ca. 1912 (Box 9, Folder 261)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 262)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce, 1911 Apr 19 (Box 9, Folder 263)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1912, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - Aunt Gertrude, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 265)
  - Boyce, Henry Harrison to
    - Boyce, Mary Ella Smith, 1898, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 266)
  - Boyce, Mary Ella Smith to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1918, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood, 1921, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 268)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce, 1912-18 (Box 9, Folder 269)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1933-37, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 270-71)
    - Her mother, 1888 Apr 26 (Box 9, Folder 272)
  - Bright, Blanche Deino (Mrs. Edward Hamilton Bright, Sr.) to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1930-34, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 273)
  - Bright, Edward Hamilton to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 274)
  - Bright, Edward ("Ned") to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1939-46, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 275-77)
  - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood to
    - Boyce, Mary Ella Smith, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 278)
    - Bright, Blanche Deino, 1945 Nov 15 (Box 9, Folder 279)
    - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood, 1924-35 (Box 9, Folder 280)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1919 Jul 18 (Box 9, Folder 281)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 282)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1924-39 (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - Hapgood, William Powers and Eleanor Page, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 284)
    - Aunt Bea, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 285)
  - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1934-46 (Box 9, Folder 286)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1921-44, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 287)
    - Hapgood, Tamsin Hughes, 1944 Jun 17 (Box 9, Folder 288)
  - Faust, Luke ("Lukie") to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 289)
  - Faust, Victoria to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1945 Mar 22 (Box 9, Folder 290)
  - Fry, Eileen Hughes to
    - Hapgood, Tamsin Hughes, 1945 Nov 4 (Box 9, Folder 291)
  - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917) to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1915 Jan 22 (Box 9, Folder 292)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances, 1911-16 (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1897-1916 (Box 9, Folder 294)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1904-16, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 295-98)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1902-12, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 299)
    - Hapgood, Seth and Lydia Seaver Wilson, 1857-99 (Box 10, Folder 300-01)
  - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82) to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 302)
    - Faust, Luke H. and Beatrix Hapgood, 1924-25 (Box 10, Folder 303)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1915-18 (Box 10, Folder 304)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 305)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1911-46, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 306-10)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1928 Jan 12 (Box 10, Folder 311)
  - Hapgood, Eleanor Page to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1925, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 312)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1938-40, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 313)
  - Hapgood, Elizabeth Kempley Reynolds to
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 314)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 315)
  - Hapgood, Emma Frances to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), 1912-14, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 316)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1922 Jun 9 (Box 10, Folder 317)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1908 Dec 24 (Box 10, Folder 318)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1918-21 (Box 10, Folder 319)
    - Hapgood, Seth, 1849 (Box 10, Folder 320)
  - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 321)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1913-21 (Box 10, Folder 322)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce, 1911-17 (Box 10, Folder 323)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1911-20, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 324)
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson and Emma Frances, 1890-99 (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1912-19, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 326)
  - Hapgood, Harry Boyce to
    - Boyce, Helen Faith, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 327)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917) and Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1911-15, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 328)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1911-15 (Box 10, Folder 329)
    - Santa Claus, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 330)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), 1880-1916, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 331-34)
    - Hapgood, Eleanor Page, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 335)
    - Hapgood, Elizabeth Kempley Reynolds, 1933-40 (Box 11, Folder 336)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances, 1886-1920 (Box 11, Folder 337-41)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1887-1922 (Box 11, Folder 342-45)
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson, 1894-1901 (Box 11, Folder 346)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1897-1900 (Box 11, Folder 347-56)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1901-13 (Box 12, Folder 357-75)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1530
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1914-43, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 376-95)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce: fragments, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 396)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1890 Jun 1 (Box 14, Folder 397)
    - Hapgood, Powers, 1937-44 (Box 14, Folder 398)
    - Hapgood, Ruth, 1932 Dec 20 (Box 14, Folder 399)
    - Hapgood, William Powers, 1916-44, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 400)
    - Hess, Fanny, 1896 Dec 27 (Box 14, Folder 401)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1915-48, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 402-14)
    - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood, 1915-45, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 415)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1915-20 (Box 14, Folder 416-17)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1921-29 (Box 15, Folder 418-34)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1929-34 (Box 16, Folder 435-52)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1935-44 (Box 17, Folder 453-70)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1945-47, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 471-72)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce, 1909-18 (Box 18, Folder 473-75)
  - Hapgood, Mary Donovan to
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1935 Jan 29 (Box 18, Folder 476)
  - Hapgood, Neith Boyce to
    - Bonnell, Margaret Boyce, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 477)
    - Boyce, Edward Colton, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 478)
    - Boyce, Mary Ella Smith, 1906 Oct 10 (Box 18, Folder 479)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917) and Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1899-1922, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 480-84)
    - Hapgood, Elizabeth Kempley Reynolds, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 485)
    - Hapgood, Emilie Bigelow, 1906 (Box 18, Folder 486)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances, 1899-1906 (Box 18, Folder 487)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1898-99 (Box 18, Folder 488-95)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1900-27 (Box 19, Folder 496-512)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1928-39, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 513-18)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins: fragments, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 519)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1899, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 520)
    - Hapgood, Tamsin Hughes, 1941-44 (Box 20, Folder 521)
    - Hapgood, William Powers, 1940-45, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 522)
    - Aunt Gertrude, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 523)
  - Hapgood, Norman to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), 1911-15, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 524)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1923-32 (Box 20, Folder 525)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances, 1878-1914, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 526)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1913-14, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 527)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1914-43, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 528-29)
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson, 1888 Dec 31 (Box 20, Folder 530)
    - Hapgood, William Powers, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 531)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Jr. to
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 532)
  - Hapgood, Powers to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917) and Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1913 Jul 11 (Box 20, Folder 533)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1927-43 (Box 20, Folder 534)
    - Hapgood, Eleanor Page, 1935 Feb 13 (Box 20, Folder 535)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances, 1913 Jul 9 (Box 20, Folder 536)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1927-39, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 537)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1924-27 (Box 20, Folder 538)
  - Hapgood, Ruth to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), 1914 Nov 18 (Box 20, Folder 539)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1926, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 540)
  - Hapgood, Tamsin Hughes to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1927-30 (Box 20, Folder 541)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1941-43 (Box 20, Folder 542)
  - Hapgood, Warren to
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), 1894 (Box 20, Folder 543)
  - Hapgood, William Powers to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1950 Jan 11 (Box 20, Folder 544)
    - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood, 1949 Dec 19 (Box 20, Folder 545)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), 1881 (Box 20, Folder 546)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1927-50 (Box 20, Folder 547)
    - Hapgood, Elizabeth Kempley Reynolds, 1940-42 (Box 20, Folder 548)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 549)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 550)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1917-42 (Box 20, Folder 551-54)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1942-43, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 555-56)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1927-46, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 557)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1924-37 (Box 21, Folder 558)
    - Hapgood, Powers, 1936-37 (Box 21, Folder 559)
  - Hess, Reuben L. to
    - Unidentified family member, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 560)
  - Reklaitis, Elizabeth Boyce to
    - Boyce, Charles, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 561)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), 1936-45 (Box 21, Folder 562)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, 1937-44, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 563-65)
    - Hapgood, Tamsin Hughes, 1944 Dec 31 (Box 21, Folder 566)
  - Walker, Flora H. to
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson, 1870 Jun 2 (Box 21, Folder 567)
  - Wayland, Heman L. to
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson, 1897 Feb 17 (Box 21, Folder 568)
  - Aunt Bea to
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 569)
  - Aunt Gertrude to
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, 1943 Aug 21 (Box 21, Folder 570)
  - Unidentified, 1894-1935, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 571)
- Writings, 1893-1977; Series III; 9.5; (23 boxes)
  Series III, Writings (Boxes 22-44), is divided into two subseries, Hutchins Hapgood and Neith Boyce Hapgood.
  - HUTCHINS HAPGOOD
    Materials in the Hutchins Hapgood subseries are divided into three sections, Books, Plays, and Shorter Works and are arranged alphabetically by title of work except book reviews, which are arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Books
      - "Christine"
        - Holograph, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 572-77)
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 578-81)
        - Draft fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 582-86)
      - David, the Story of a Soul
        - Preface, notes, ca. 1913 (Box 22, Folder 587)
        - Draft A, typescript, ca. 1913 (Box 22, Folder 588-91)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, ca. 1913 (Box 22, Folder 592-94)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, ca. 1913 (Box 23, Folder 595)
        - Draft B, typescript, ca. 1913 (Box 23, Folder 596-98)
        - Galley proofs, 1913 Oct (Box 23, Folder 599)
        - Copyright certificate and agreement, 1913 May (Box 23, Folder 600)
        - Printed version in The Musical Advance, pp. 3-6 [installment], 1913 (Box 23, Folder 601)
          See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1531
      - "Letters from a Ballet Girl"
        See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1532
        - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 602-07)
        - Draft B, holograph, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 608)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 609-11)
      - "My Forty Years of Drink"
        - Draft A, typescript and holograph (Box 23, Folder 612-14)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 615-17)
        - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 618-20)
      - "The New Baby"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 621)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 622)
      - The Relativity of Man: galley proofs, 1925 Dec (Box 24, Folder 623-25)
      - The Spirit of the Ghetto
        - Book reviews [reprint], 1967 Mar 19 (Box 24, Folder 626)
        - Correspondence, 1947 Oct 29 (Box 24, Folder 627)
      - The Story of a Lover
        - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 628-32)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 633-36)
        - Draft B, fragments, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 637)
        - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 638-41)